Item one... Duck!
Cubert, you crapscallion!
Why aren't you in school?
I couldn't get past
the protestors.
A bunch of smiling,
angry people
were handing out
these anti-evolution flyers.
Evolution is under attack
in our schools?
To the Science Mobile!
You mean the ship?
Yes. The Science Mobile!
It's just that you've never
called it that before, but okay.
I don't understand evolution,
and I have to protect my kids
from understanding it!
We will not give in
to the thinkers!
You people are as loud
as you are ignorant.
Now, get back on your turnip trucks and go home!
That is an insultingly accurate stereotype, sir!
As a professor of science,
I assure you that we did, in fact,
evolve from filthy monkey-men!
I cannot speak for you, sir,
but my ancestors
were not monkeys.
They were orangutans.
Hard-working,
patriotic orangutans.
Dr. Banjo?
In the fur.
And I remind you that
evolution is merely a theory,
like gravity,
or the shape of the Earth.
Hey, Professor, I'm a flying spaghetti monster.
You seriously believe I'm descended
from some kind of flightless manicotti?
Yes!
Oh, please.
A far more logical
explanation is
the undisprovable
science of Creatureism.
All life was created in its
present form 7,000 years ago
by a fantastical creature
from outer space!
Bunk!
Oh!
If your elitist East Coast
evolution is real,
why has no one found
the missing link
between modern humans
and ancient apes?
We did find it.
It's called Homo erectus.
Then you have proven
my case, sir,
for no one has found the link
between apes and this Homo erectus.
Yes, they have!
It's called Homo habilis.
Ah-ha!
But no one has found
the missing link
between ape and this so-called Homo habilis.
Yes, they have!
It's called
Australopithecus africanus!
Oh-ho! I've got you now.
Fair enough, but where, then, is the missing link
between apes
and this Darwinius masillae?
Answer me that,
Professor!
Okay, granted, that one
missing link is still missing,
but just because we haven't found
it doesn't mean it doesn't exist!
Things don't exist simply
because you believe in them.
Thus sayeth the Almighty Creature in the Sky!
I'll show that
banana-swilling poop-slinger!
We just need to find
that last missing link.
I found a missing link. It seems
to be half man, half toucan.
Not what we're looking for.
Throw it in the soup.
And here's something.
Uh-oh. It's another one
of Fry's dogs.
You find something, Hermes?
Ah, no.
I hate chiseling
right after a manicure.
Oh! Darn it! I broke off one of my fingers!
Look, Cubert.
The neck on this one.
I bet he spent
a fortune on ties!
What, too soon?
I highly doubt a Jurassic
elaphrosaurid had access to neckwear.
I knew I should have gone with
the ring-around-the-collar joke.
Hey, look!
I found a robot fossil!
That's a bedspring,
you dumb bedspring!
There are no robot fossils.
What? Who says
I didn't evolve?
Everybody!
Robots were created quite
recently. It was in all the papers.
Then explain this!
I've hit
a rich vein of missing links.
Java man, Piltdown man,
Manfred Mann.
Eureka!
It's the elusive
missing missing link.
This will show Banjo,
once and for all.
Yeah!
What the...
Oh, That's mine.
Hmm. My tux doesn't fit.
Probably because I've grown
so much since I last wore it.
Or evolved,
one might say.
One might not say that.
Your tux doesn't fit because
you stole it from a boy.
You mean a man.
It was his Bar Mitzvah.
Welcome, museum members.
Or, as I like to call you,
future exhibits.
He's good.
Tonight we have a new resident
here in the Hall of Hominids,
generously donated by its
discoverer, Hubert Farnsworth.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Homo Farnsworth.
Once again,
science saves the day.
The end.
And now, to discuss the scientific
implications of this discovery,
our new museum curator,
Dr. Banjo!
Thank you, Professor Farnsworth,
for your generous gift,
which has, once and for all,
disproven evolution.
Behold! Homo Farnsworth,
frolicking with dinosaurs
at the moment of creation.
I don't want to live
on this planet anymore.
Faster! Faster!
Just drop me off
at that asteroid over there.
Wow, this planetoid
is completely lifeless.
Not lifeless enough!
Set up my shack so I can kick you out of it!
Professor, is this
your only water source?
It looks like
Diet Dr. Pepper.
It's not that bad. It's just
laden with toxic minerals.
But not for long.
What's in the tube?
Microscopic Nanobots.
They're tiny robots I designed
to eat up nasty irritants.
Speaking of nasty irritants,
what's gonna become of Cubert?
Who? Oh, my son.
Don't worry. He's been safely
abandoned with his godfather.
Cubert, I felt we needed
some father-son bonding time,
so I found a couple of baseball
gloves and boiled them up for lunch.
Why don't you
just go to hell!
Wait! We still have to
discuss the facts of life.
What are they?
Okay, I finished moving
the last grand piano.
Now can we have our pizza?
You'll get your damn pizza, you parasite!
First, let's see if my Nanobots
have purified the water yet.
The water's as sterile
as my milkman-trusting father.
But what's this?
The Nanobots have
gotten more complex.
What's that you say?
Those robots evolved
all by themselves, you say?
It wasn't by themselves.
I put them there.
I'm a genius.
Get over it!
Hey, look.
Now they got bigger.
Good heavens!
Trilobots!
Oh, no! My sunglasses were in there!
Get off!
Let's get the pizza
out of here!
Look, there's a cave-like hole
in that mountain.
It might be a cave.
Does anyone have
a lighter?
Hang on.
Okay, we have shelter
and just enough precious food
to ward off starvation.
It's pizza time!
Pineapple?
Oh, man!
So much for that.
Hello. I remembered
you liked superheroes,
so I painted you a mural
on your wall.
This is Father-Man.
He fights crime to earn Son-Boy's respect.
Is it working?
This is sucky!
You suck! Who taught you to do
three-point perspective?
I could make a better mural
with my butt!
Father-Man away.
Nothing like a cave
for a good night's sleep.
So, what do we got to eat that's
not poisoned with pineapple?
I packed plenty of food, but
it's all in dehydrated pill form.
Then we need water
from that pond.
We'll have to fight our way
past the Trilobots.
Go! Go! Hit anything that moves!
Whoa.
Wow.
A whole forest
grew overnight.
All these trees are robotic.
I can't believe how quickly
they sprung up.
I can. Robots do everything
faster, including evolving
and believing how quickly things spring up.
One thing about Bristol-Myers
Squibb, they know how to cook a steak.
Hey, look at me.
I'm the Ty-D-Bol Man.
I own a yacht,
and everybody poops on me!
Help! Police!
Everybody grab a club.
Oh, big, tough water guy, why don't
you come up here on land and...
Look out for the next thing!
Great Scott,
a Tricycle-tops.
Throw down,
dinosaurs of the land and sea.
This is a cool way to die!
Dr. Zoidberg?
I'm sorry for treating
you like a total Zoidberg...
I mean, loser.
Go on.
It's just that
I get bullied a lot.
I guess I kind of make fun of
people as a defense mechanism.
Hey, Cubert,
is that your family mansion?
Why don't you ask your mom?
She's coming over for a sex visit.
Don't worry, I know how to handle bullies.
Just pretend like
you're pathetic.
Help, I'm scared!
I wet myself.
I'm crying like a baby
and I'm soaking in pee,
but what else is new?
The pee-babies
peed themselves.
I'm off to pottery class,
dorkwads.
And that's that.
Whoa! You're like some kind of dumpster Jedi.
So, you want to
come in maybe?
I've got a nice pound cake
with a footprint on it.
Don't eat my butt!
If this is anything like killing
that pigeon on my balcony,
we've got our work
cut out for us.
Look out, a solar flare!
What the shmell happened?
A mass extinction.
That solar flare created a
huge electromagnetic pulse
that, while harmless
to organic life,
short-circuited
the robo-dinosaurs.
Convenient.
Only puny mammal-like robots
cowering in caves
could survive such
a catastrophe.
Guys, guys!
I taught myself to knit.
Wait a moment.
If we could scavenge the right
parts from these robo-dinos,
I might be able to construct
a rudimentary spaceship
to get us off this planet!
Oh, well, it took almost
two hours, but it's finished.
Now let's go to sleep.
It's solar powered, so we
can't take off until sunrise.
Well, let's find something
comfy to bed down on.
Hey, looky here.
Sweet robot swan
of Botswana!
Looks like the fittest did a
little surviving last night, huh?
Whatever.
Hey, looky there.
Those robo-cavemen have
kidnapped our human regular-women.
We gotta save them!
But the only weapon we have
is my fan dance.
Hmm. I believe I can fashion a
slingshot using this robot wishbone
and this elastic
from my pants.
I think they want wives,
so just play along.
If it doesn't work out, we'll
still get half their rocks.
I can earn my own rocks.
Also, I don't want any rocks.
Well, it took almost 12 hours,
but it's finished.
It's too dark now,
but first thing tomorrow,
we'll slingshot them
like they've never
been slangshat.
What's going on?
How did we save you?
It was
the weirdest thing.
We went to sleep, and when we woke
up, our cave husbands were gone.
I'm gonna miss Spencer.
Don't be afraid, little guys.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Nice net.
You can speak?
Dread my locks!
A fully-evolved robot human!
I'm Dr. Widnar,
a naturalist.
And I'm Bender, baby.
My human slaves and I
come from a planet
where organic life and robotic
life evolved side by side.
Oh, shut up!
Amazing.
I've theorized that carbon-based,
fat-filled life could exist,
but until today,
I never had any proof.
Good for you.
Can we go home now?
Welcome, museum members,
or as I like to call you,
future exhibits.
I now present
my latest discovery,
the amazing non-mechanical man, Homo Farnsworth.
Thank you.
I must say, I'm so proud to
see what you've blossomed into
since I first created
your ancestors.
What?
I thought you knew.
You all evolved from some
filth-gobbling Nanobots I designed.
I dumped them in one of your ponds a few days ago.
But this is
creationist talk.
He speaks lies!
The Earth was created
in eons, not days.
Yes, relative to you,
it was eons,
but, well, look at this hologram
I took the day before yesterday
of a robot frolicking
with a robo-dinosaur.
I don't want to live
on this planet anymore.
You're under arrest
for crimes against science.
No!
Could you drag me
by the restroom?
Go back to Roboklahoma!
Order! In the matter of Everyone v. Farnsworth,
the alleged creationist faces
a sentence of death by melting.
Who is representing
the accused?
I am.
I am, Your Honor.
Bender, what the hell
are you doing?
Shut up, I'm billing you by the hour!
Besides, I'm a robot,
they'll listen to me.
Ladytrons and gentlebots...
Objection. In the absence of pants,
defense's suspenders serve no purpose.
I'm going to allow them
for now.
Thank you. Your Honor,
this meat-man does not deny
that we robots are the
glorious product of evolution.
He claims only to have played a small
role in supplying the initial machinery.
I ask you,
is that so crazy?
Yes, it's completely crazy,
and that is why you must find him
not guilty by reason of insanity!
Objection! I'm not crazy.
I created you all,
and I came here in a homemade
spaceship and lived in a cave.
If you don't believe me,
ask my uncle.
Prosecutor,
your opening statement?
Yeah, honey,
I'll be home for dinner.
The prosecution rests,
Your Honor.
Very well.
We will reconvene when the jury reaches a verdict.
Son, you in
a whole mess of trouble.
What?
Has the jury reached
a verdict?
No, we have not,
for we have evolved to a
higher state of consciousness.
In the grand scheme, all
physical beings are but yokels.
Now, settle your petty
squabbles and get the hell out.
That'll be $10,000.
Well, digital photographs
don't lie.
I admit that what you witnessed may
have been some form of evolution.
I'm glad you agree,
Dr. Banjo.
Evolution set in motion by a
wise and all-knowing creator.
You.
Well, I don't know
about all-knowing.
And I admit it's possible,
however unlikely,
that some wise
and all-knowing alien monster
set evolution in motion
here on Earth.
Oh, oh, and the creator
could also be a robot.
Then who built
this so-called creator robot?
Some magical bearded robot
in the sky?
I guess that would be stupid. Never mind.
Then it's settled.
Finally, a world in which
I'm happy to raise my son.
Good, 'cause I'm
sick of him.
I'm serious.
He's a terrible person.